Jackson Meier

(513) 265-4090 | jackson.meier423@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/jackson-meier | Possess Active TS/SCI clearance

SUMMARY

Motivated, performance-oriented U.S. Navy Veteran with leadership experience. Currently enrolled in a Coding Bootcamp with UC San Diego Extension and quickly becoming proficient in numerous front-end and back-end technologies. An enthusiastic team-player with excellent communication and interpersonal skills. Able to learn new concepts quickly due to strong problem-solving skills and an analytical mindset.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java
- Platforms and Frameworks: Git, Bootstrap, Express.js, Node.js
- Libraries: jQuery, React.js, Sequelize.js
- Databases: MongoDB, MySQL
- .

EXPERIENCE

Intelligence Officer | U.S. Navy | November 2018 - present Coronado, CA

- Responsible for developing comprehensive threat assessments on adversary's strengths, weaknesses, capabilities, and intentions
- Conducted briefs to both peers and senior ranking officials in order to provide understanding on multiple complex issues
- Inventoried and safeguarded classified materials
- Maintained a database on Microsoft Excel to track information on members' security clearances

Submarine Officer | U.S. Navy | August 2017-November 2018 Charleston, SC and Ballston Spa, NY

- Attended and graduated Naval Nuclear Power School
- Led sailors in the safe operation of a S7G nuclear reactor
- · Conducted numerous technical evolutions with mechanical, electrical, and reactor subsystems

Sailing Instructor | U.S. Navy | June 2017-August 2017 Annapolis, MD

- Effectively taught over 100 Naval Academy freshmen basic sailing and seamanship through constructive teaching and communication
- Led clear instruction in both the classroom and in a Navy 26-foot sailboat

EDUCATION

UC San Diego Extension | June 2020-September 2020

- Portfolio: https://meierj423.github.io/portfolio-page-v2/
- GitHub: https://github.com/meierj423

Bachelor of Science (with Merit)

Mathematics | United States Naval Academy | Annapolis, MD | June 2013-May 2017

- Mathematics and Electrical Engineering tutor
- Special Olympics track and field coach: Spring 2014-2017

New Mexico Military Institute | Roswell, NM | August 2012-May 2013

- Roger Staubach Annapolis Prep Scholar Recipient
- Phi Theta Kappa Member